Guide to the William McGuire papers, 1946-2004.
McGuire, William papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
William McGuire papers, 1946-2004.
16-4-4028
William, McGuire, 1920-
5.5 cubic feet.
Printed material, reports, correspondence, photographs.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Collection includes consulting files for projects including Armco Steel Corporation design of rigid frame buildings and roof systems; Power Reactor Development Corp. study of containment of fast breeder reactor; Buckminster Fuller design of Museum of Modern Art exhibit; Gibbs & Hill prestressed concrete nuclear containment vessel studies;Central Hudson Gas & Electric Corp. implosion of large steam generator; National Bureau of Standards structural integrity of U.S. Olympic structure, Lake Placid and the investigation of the Hyatt Regency Walkway collapse; C. Lindbergh & Associates review of the design of the structure of a very large engine test facility in Tullahoma, TN; Visual Edge Ltd development of ELRFD, an electronic version of the AISC LRFD specification; OSHA the L'Ambiance Plaza collapse; and work on the Green Bank Telescope in West Virginia. Also Cornell projects, including the Fall Creek Suspension Bridge; student notes; and lecture notes for Cornell engineering classes.
Also plans for the Hyatt Regency Hotel (Kansas City, Missouri); for L'Ambiance Plaza (Bridgeport, Connecticut), and for the Triphammer Falls Foot Bridge.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor of Civil and Environmental Engineering. Bill McGuire, an expert in steel structures, received a B.S. degree from Bucknell University in 1942 and, after serving in the U.S. Navy during World War II, an M.C.E. degree from Cornell in 1947. From 1947 to 1949, he worked for Jackson & Moreland Engineers as a structural designer of power plants and atomic energy projects. He returned to Cornell in 1949, was promoted to associate professor in 1952 and professor in 1960. He served as director of Civil Engineering from 1966-1968, and retired in 1989. He was the author of two influential textbooks: "Steel Structures" and "Matrix Structural Analysis." His consulting as a licensed professional engineer included the design of special structures and the investigation of structural failures. He was deeply involved in the planning design, upgrade, and maintenance of the radio telescope at Arecibo. He was also the co-designer of the Fall Creek Suspension Bridge.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Collection includes consulting files for projects including Armco Steel Corporation design of rigid frame buildings and roof systems; Power Reactor Development Corp. study of containment of fast breeder reactor; Buckminster Fuller design of Museum of Modern Art exhibit; Gibbs & Hill prestressed concrete nuclear containment vessel studies;Central Hudson Gas & Electric Corp. implosion of large steam generator; National Bureau of Standards structural integrity of U.S. Olympic structure, Lake Placid and the investigation of the Hyatt Regency Walkway collapse; C. Lindbergh & Associates review of the design of the structure of a very large engine test facility in Tullahoma, TN; Visual Edge Ltd development of ELRFD, an electronic version of the AISC LRFD specification; OSHA the L'Ambiance Plaza collapse; and work on the Green Bank Telescope in West Virginia. Also Cornell projects, including the Fall Creek Suspension Bridge; student notes; and lecture notes for Cornell engineering classes.
Also plans for the Hyatt Regency Hotel (Kansas City, Missouri); for L'Ambiance Plaza (Bridgeport, Connecticut), and for the Triphammer Falls Foot Bridge.
SUBJECTS
Names:
McGuire, William, 1920-; Fuller, R. Buckminster (Richard Buckminster), 1895-1983.; Fuller, R. Buckminster (Richard Buckminster), 1895-1983; Armco Steel Corporation.; Power Reactor Development Corporation.; Museum of Modern Art (New York, N.Y.) -- Exhibitions.; Cornell University. College of Civil and Environmental Engineering.; Gibbs & Hill.; Central Hudson Gas & Electric Corporation.; United States. National Bureau of Standards.; Kansas City Hyatt Regency.; United States. Occupational Safety and Health Administration.; L'Ambiance Plaza (Bridgeport, Conn.); C. Lindbergh & Associates.; National Radio Astronomy Observatory (U.S.); Armco Steel Corporation; Gibbs & Hill; Kansas City Hyatt Regency; L'Ambiance Plaza (Bridgeport, Conn.); Museum of Modern Art (New York, N.Y.); National Radio Astronomy Observatory (U.S.); United States. National Bureau of Standards; United States. Occupational Safety and Health Administration; Olympic Games; Olympic Games
Subjects:
Civil engineering -- Study and teaching.; Structural engineering -- Study and teaching.; Power reactors.; Nuclear reactors.; Structural failures -- Investigation.; Building failures -- Investigation. -- Kansas City; Building failures -- Investigation. -- Bridgeport; Bridges -- Ithaca.; Astronomy -- Green Bank.; Astronomy; Bridges; Building failures -- Investigation; Civil engineering -- Study and teaching; Nuclear reactors; Structural engineering -- Study and teaching; Structural failures -- Investigation
Places:
Connecticut -- Bridgeport; Missouri -- Kansas City; New York (State) -- Ithaca; West Virginia -- Green Bank
Form and Genre Terms:
Exhibition catalogs
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Consulting Files
Series II. Green Bank Telescope (GBT)
Series III. Cornell material
Series IV. William McGuire's Drawings
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Consulting Files
  - Central Hudson - Design Review, 1977-09-1978-01 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Computations and handwritten notes
  - Central Hudson - Assorted, 1963, 1967, 1974-1984 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Correspondence, handwritten notes
  - Central Hudson - Roseton Station Boiler, 1978-1981 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Central Hudson - Analysis and Computation Corrections, Oct 1978 - Mar 1979, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Central Hudson - Torsion Analysis, 1971, 1978-1982, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Handwritten calculations, Handbook of Structural Stability (Tokyo)
  - Central Hudson - Discussion with Combustion and Design Reviews, 1951, 1978-1981 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Articles, informational pamphlets
  - Central Hudson - Proposal for Tests, 1972-1978, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Handwritten notes; Engineering Journal article; catalog; drawings
  - Central Hudson - Beam Tests, 1976-07-1978-11 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Photographs; drawing plans; handwritten notes
  - Central Hudson - European Projects, 1980-1983, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Correspondence; contents are in German; design plans; pamphlets of MAN Stahlhochbau and EVT Energie- und Verfahrenstechnik GmbH
  - Correspondence on Reinforcement + Buckstay and Steel Fix-Up Report and Sketches (1 of 2), 1981-08-1983-01 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence on Reinforcement + Buckstay and Steel Fix-Up Report and Sketches (2 of 2), 1981-08-1983-01 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Buckstay System at Roseton, Oct 1968, Aug 1981 - Sep 1981 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Handwritten notes and drawings; no page numbered 119; sketch plan of Roseton Steam Generating Station
  - Lake Placid - Final Report Analysis, 1979-08-16 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Barzun and Lieberman Articles, 1969-11-1981-11 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous - Cornell, 1970-1983 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - V.D.X Course, Guyed Towers Design and Analysis, 1947, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - News and Magazine Articles, 2001-09-2003-09 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence on Structural Analysis and Engineering, 2003-09-2003-10 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Armco - Correspondence (1 of 2), 1955 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Armco - Correspondence (2 of 2), 1955-1966 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Armco - Preliminary Computations, 1955-02-1955-06 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Pittsburgh - Des Moines Steel Company, 1953-1965 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Pittsburgh - Des Moines - Solar Furnace, 1957-1959 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Webrib Steel Corporation - Article, Oct 1938, Dec 1949 - Jul 1952, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Fatigue tests, article
  - Webrib Steel Corporation - Correspondence, Feb 1952 - Feb 1955, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Eckerlin and Klepper Consulting Engineers - Correspondence, 1950-1956, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Mini photo album; business card; card with cartoon of Hitler; booklet titled The Architect and the Structural Engineer
  - Fuller, R. Buckminster - Correspondence, 1959-1960, 1988, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Fuller, R. Buckminster - Radome, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Report on radome testing
  - Fuller, R. Buckminster - Museum of Modern Art, 1959-05-1959-06 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Jackson and Moreland, Engineers, 1932, 1947-1964 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Pamphlet on The Charles Leavitt Edgar Station
  - Armand L. Adams - Chair Swing Failure, Feb 1963 - May 1963, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Correspondence and computations
  - Asian Institute of Technology - Correspondence, 1970-1984, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Wedding photo; AIT Review; Christmas letter; Christmas card from Thailand; RSVP to Royal Opening of the New Campus of AIT; AIT Pamphlet; articles
  - Report on the Brady Street Bridge Accident of May 23, 1978, 1981-02-09 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Original folder titled "Winner Core Report - original"
  - U.S. Olympic Stadium, 1978-1980 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Correspondence, articles, and reports
  - Olympic Stadium - Notes, 1978-1980, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Hyatt Regency Hotel Request - Dynamic Analysis, Sep 28, 1981, Dec 03, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Hyatt Regency Hotel, 1971, 1981-1984, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
    Undated articles, sketches, handwritten notes
  - Power Reactor Development Company (PRDC) Correspondence, 1956-1963 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Power Reactor Development Company (PRDC) Computations, 1956-1959 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    Undated "Directions for Operating Faultless 'SO' (Slide Operating) Ring Binder"
  - Power Reactor Development Company (PRDC) Contracts and Extensions, 1956-1963 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    An official agreement between Power Reactor Development Company and William McGuire and Gordon P. Fisher
  - Power Reactor Development Company (PRDC) - Materials - Shielding, 1951-1963, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
    Program for American Society of Civil Engineers (ASCE) Environmental Engineering Conference; diagram for atomic power plant fission products containment barriers; copy of student report
  - Power Reactor Development Company (PRDC) - 7 psi second Accident, 1960, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    ASCE Transactions: Containment Studies for an Atomic Power Plant
  - Power Reactor Development Company (PRDC) - Detroit Trip, 1962-09-14 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    Handwritten notes and questions
  - Power Reactor Development Company (PRDC) - Secondary Shield Concrete Problem, Reactor Vessel Problem, Mar 1960 - Jun 1960, undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Power Reactor Development Company (PRDC) - Static Pressure Problem, 1960-03 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Power Reactor Development Company (PRDC) - Secondary Shield Wall Cutout, 1961-1962, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Power Reactor Development Company (PRDC) - Job Specifications, 1956-06 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Power Reactor Development Company (PRDC) - Correspondence, Miscellaneous, 1956-1960 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Power Reactor Development Company (PRDC) - Chicago Bridge and Iron Company Computations, 1957, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Power Reactor Development Company (PRDC) - Notes and Articles on Reactors, 1955-1963, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - American Institute of Steel Construction (AISC) - Tests - Correspondence, 1959-1966 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Pictures, film
  - American Institute of Steel Construction (AISC) - Industrial Fasteners Institute (IFI) - Behavior on Bolts in Tension - Karl de Vries Letter, 1961-1963 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - American Institute of Steel Construction (AISC) - Industrial Fasteners Institute (IFI) - Approximations for Designs, 1963-01-1963-10 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - American Institute of Steel Construction (AISC) - Industrial Fasteners Institute (IFI) - Project - Bolt - Stage Deformation Computations, 1961-1962, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Proposal - Research on Bolted Connections in Fatigue, 1963-04-1964-01 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Jones and Laughlin Ladles - W McGuire, 1951, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - A.S. Wikstrom - Drilling Platform, 1956, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    Photos; Proposed drilling platform sketch; Connecticut turnpike sketch
  - A.S. Wikstrom - Niagara Mohawk Caisson, 1950-1951, 1959-1966 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Triphammer Falls Foot Bridge, Feb 1960 - May 1960, Dec 1996 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Tishman Realty and Construction Co - Preliminary, 1957-1961, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Tishman Realty and Construction Co - Expenses, 1959-1962, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
    American Airlines boarding pass; undated receipts
  - Tishman Realty and Construction Co - Kawneer Co, 1957-1959 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    Sketches by Kawneer; Pittsburgh Plate Glass Company files
  - Tishman Realty and Construction Co - Glass Tests, 1958-1961, 1975, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
    Photos of broken pane
  - New York Convention Center/I.M. Pei, 1980-1985 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Correspondence and notes
  - New York Convention Center: Test Frame Analysis, 1983, Sep 1984 - Nov 1984, undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Leonard Church Urquhart Handbook, 1956-1967, 1994, undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Dallas, Tuscon, Houghton, Michigan Trips, 1984-04-1984-05 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    Tourist map of Michigan; boarding pass
  - Zetlin-Argo Structural Investigations Inc., Jan 1981, Aug 1984 - May 1985, undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
    Correspondence and articles; handwritten notes
  - Ralph A. Winner, Jr. vs Commonwealth - Correspondence, Photos, and Reports, 1976-1981 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Report of a Test for The Triangle Steel Company, 1983-10-10 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    Photos
  - Structural Investigation of Some Elements of the Aeropropulsion Systems Test Facility at the Arnold Engineering Development Center, Apr 1983 - Aug 1983, undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
    Includes correspondence, comments, computations+
  - Hale And Dorr, Counsellors at Law, 1973-1975, 1984, undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
    Correspondence; reports on John Hancock building and wind-induced motion of buildings; Planning and Environmental Criteria for Tall Buildings
  - National Bureau of Standards - East Chicago, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    Correspondence and articles; Investigation of Construction Failure of the Riley Road Interchange Ramp, East Chicago, Indiana
  - Tullahoma Report, 1982-08-30 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Tullahoma Report Draft, 1982-08-30 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Tullahoma Review Panel, 1981-1983, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Pamphlet for Arnold Engineering Development Center (AEDC); pamphelt for AEDC Test Highlights; A Limited Investigation of the Aeropropulsion Systems Test Facility (ASTF)
  - Tullahoma - Direct Intersections, 1973-1982, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Articles, sketches; copies of printed text by the American Institute of Steel Construction Engineering Journal; pamphlet of Heron: Geometrical non-linearity in collapse analysis of thick shells
  - A.B. Chance - Switch Tanks, 1983-02-1983-05 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Central Hudson - Assorted, 1971, Feb 1983 - Oct 1983, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
    Photos; correspondence; articles
  - Central Hudson Gas and Electric - Bills and Expenses, Apr 1977 - Jan 1984, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
    Agreement made among Central Hudson, Consolidated Edison Company of New York, and Niagara Mohawk Power Corporation
  - Roseton Boiler Reinforcements/Steam Generator + Combustion Engineering + Buckstay Systems - Assorted Documents (1 of 4), 1969-1982, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
    Copies of texts, computations, correspondence (including Raymond J. Falcon), pamphlets, sketched design plans; Lateral Buckling of Buckstay Systems Using Wide Flange Shapes; Boiler Stiffening report
  - Roseton Boiler Reinforcements/Steam Generator + Combustion Engineering + Buckstay Systems - Assorted Documents (2 of 4), 1969-1982, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Roseton Boiler Reinforcements/Steam Generator + Combustion Engineering + Buckstay Systems - Assorted Documents (3 of 4), 1969-1982, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Roseton Boiler Reinforcements/Steam Generator + Combustion Engineering + Buckstay Systems - Assorted Documents (4 of 4), 1969-1982, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Ramada Inn - Greg G. D., 1970, 1983-1990, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
    Copy of New York State Uniform Fire Prevention and Building Code
  - National Bureau of Standards - Lake Placid Bills, 1979-02-1980-01 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Power Reactor Development Company (PRDC) - Notes (1 of 2), 1940, 1955-1957 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    American Society of Civil Engineers: An Investigation of Steel Rigid Frames
  - Power Reactor Development Company (PRDC) - Notes (2 of 2), 1940, 1955-1957 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Investigation of the Kansas City Hyatt Regency Walkways Collapse, 1982-02 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Investigation of L'Ambiance Plaza Building Collapse - American Society of Civil Engineers, 1991-09-26 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Investigation of L'Ambiance Plaza Building Collapse - National Bureau of Standards, 1987-09-1988 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    Photos, comments, articles
  - L'Ambiance Plaza Report, 1985-1989 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - L'Ambiance Plaza Forensics, 1988-1991, undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
    Correspondence; reports; meeting agendas
  - L'Ambiance Plaza - Visual Inspection, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    Photos of building collapse
  - Shandaken Bridge, 1987-1989, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    Inspection report, correspondence, computations; news alert in 2007: "Cracking, Vibration May Have Contributed to Collapse"
  - Structural Steel Design for Boston Edison Company and the San Jaun Steam Plant, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Report on Methods for Connecting Light Gage Steel Structural Elements - The American Iron and Steel Institute, 1952-11 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Finances, Grants, Expense Reports, 1991-1996, 2000-2005 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - The Journal of Solar Energy Science and Engineering - Volume 1, 1957-04-1957-07 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Hyatt Regency Slides (1 of 2), 1983 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Hyatt Regency Slides (2 of 2), 1983 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Laboratory of Nuclear Studies - Cornell University - Synchrotron Support, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    Blueprints and computations
  - Fall Creek Suspension Bridge - Assorted Documents (1 of 2), 1943, 1951,1959-1960, 1982, 2000, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
    United States Steel pamphlet, correspondence, computations
  - Fall Creek Suspension Bridge - Assorted Documents (2 of 2), 1959-1960, 2006-2010 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Fall Creek Suspension Bridge Notes, 1959-1960, 1977, 2011-2012 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    "Bridge Means Restriction Study" presentation
  - Fall Creek Bridge - Dean Hollister, 1960-1979, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
    An article in German; various newspaper articles
  - Central Hudson Gas and Electric - Sketch Drawings/Blueprints, 1969-1971 (Box 7)
  - Piece of Arecibo Rail, Undated (Box 7)
- Series 2. Green Bank Telescope (GBT)
  - The National Radio Astronomy Observatory (NRAO) - Green Bank Telescope - General, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    Maps of West Virginia; NRAO Brochure
  - Green Bank Telescope - Bolt Failures, 2002-11 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    Correspondence, presentation
  - Green Bank Telescope - Wheels, 1993, 2000-2003, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Green Bank Telescope - Flex Plates, 1997, 2002-2004 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Green Bank Telescope - Azimuth Wheel Assembly, 1978, 1992-2002 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Green Bank Telescope - Technical Background, 2002-10-2002-11 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Green Bank Telescope - Wheel Assembly Models, 2002-12 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - The National Radio Astronomy Observatory - Miscellaneous, 1989, 1992, 1997, 2009, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Green Bank Telescope - Review Panel Report, 2002-11-2003-03 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    Correspondence
  - Green Bank Telescope Azimuth Track Review (1 of 2), 2002-10-31-2002-11-01 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Green Bank Telescope Azimuth Track Review (2 of 2), 2002-10-31-2002-11-01 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Green Bank Telescope Azimuth Track Progress Review (1 of 3), 2004-12 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Green Bank Telescope Azimuth Track Progress Review (2 of 3), 2004-12 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Green Bank Telescope Azimuth Track Progress Review (3 of 3), 2004-12 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    Includes CD
  - Green Bank Telescope - 2004 Review, 2002-2005, undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - The National Radio Astronomy Observatory/Green Bank Telescope - 8/05 Review, 2005-07-2005-09 (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Series 3. Cornell material
  - College of Engineering Degree Committee - Transition from 5yr to 4yr Program (1 of 2), 1964-04-1964-11 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - College of Engineering Degree Committee - Transition from 5yr to 4yr Program (2 of 2), 1964-04-1964-11 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Civil Engineering Lecture Notes - 2701 (1 of 2), 1941-1950 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Civil Engineering Lecture Notes - 2701 (2 of 2), 1941-1950 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Civil Engineering Lecture Notes - 2702 (1 of 2), 1950-1954, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Civil Engineering Lecture Notes - 2702 (2 of 2), 1950-1954, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Civil Engineering Lecture Notes - 2703 (1 of 2), 1951-1955, 1964-1966 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Civil Engineering Lecture Notes - 2703 (2 of 2), 1951-1955, 1964-1966 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Civil Engineering Lecture Notes - 2713 (1 of 2), 1951-1961, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Civil Engineering Lecture Notes - 2713 (2 of 2), 1951-1961, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Civil Engineering Lecture Notes - 2703, 2706, 2713 Assorted (1 of 2), 1950-1956, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Civil Engineering Lecture Notes - 2703, 2706, 2713 Assorted (2 of 2), 1950-1956, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Student Notes - Hydrodynamics (Prof M.S. Priest), 1946 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Series 4. William McGuire's Drawings
  - Boston Edison Corp Drawings: Turbine Room Roof Trusses, 1947-11-28 (Box Tube 1)
    not related to Arecibo Telescope
  - Boston Edison Corp Drawings: Turbine Pedestal Unit #4, 1948-02 (Box Tube 1)
  - Cornell University Triphammer Falls Foot Bridge, 1960-02-23 (Box Tube 1)
    Prof. McGuire was heavily involved with the design of this foot bridge
  - Burns and Roe Drawings: Furnace Upper Backstay drawings, 1969-10-31 (Box Tube 1)
  - Burns and Roe Drawings: Furnace Guides ARRGT, 1970-05-07 (Box Tube 1)
  - Burns and Roe Drawings: Boiler Trusses, 1977-12-03 (Box Tube 1)
  - Burns and Roe Drawings: Boiler Backstays, 1977-12-03 (Box Tube 1)
  - Hyatt Regency Hotel, Kansas City, Missouri: Framing Plan, 1978-03-30 (Box Tube 1)
    William McGuire was on the committee that investigated the July 17, 1981 collapse of the atrium suspended walkway that resulted in the deaths of over 100 people.
  - Hyatt Regency Hotel, Kansas City, Missouri: Havel Steel Co, 1979-01-13 (Box Tube 1)
  - Don Campbell, 2014-06-17 (Box Tube 1)
  - Roseton Steam Generating Station, Roseton, NY, Date Unknown (Box Tube 1)